T.C. Rotunda

tcrotunda@gmail.com | (714) 883-7973

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/tcrotunda/ | GitHub: https://github.com/tcrotunda | Portfolio: https://tcrotunda.github.io/

Summary

Data Specialist with 7+ years of experience working in TV data analytics and for top financial firms such as JP Morgan, BNY Mellon, and Charles Schwab. Self-starter, fast learner, and can retain information at a high level. Motivated to learn new technologies and languages. A passion for data, and excels in team-oriented environments. Highly detail-oriented, and able to juggle multiple projects at a time. Excellent written and verbal communication skills.

Technical Skills

Scala, Python, SQL, Spark, Databricks, AWS, Tableau, JavaScript, R, HTML, CSS, Airflow, Jira, Confluence, GitHub, MS Office Suite

Employment

605 LLC Data QC Engineer

Pasadena, CA / Remote May 2021 - December 2022

- ETL Pipelines: Tested enhancements and newly created ETL pipelines related to viewership, ads, and reference data, which corresponded to over 1 billion records per day and over 50 TB in total
- Requirements Gathering: Worked closely with fellow QC Engineers, Data Engineers, and Product team to understand Business Requirements Documentation, Technical Requirements/ETL changes, and acceptance testing requirements
- Testing: Based on requirements gathering, wrote/ran Databricks notebooks containing standardized Scala scripts and created tailored Scala validations for QC testing; spotted inconsistencies in ETL code
- SQL: Created Databricks SQL validations checking for missing data across 605's multiple internal reference data tables
- **Demographics:** Responsible for quarterly validations of the core demographics data for 605, which has up to 24 different demographics fields
- Compliance: Assisted with building processes, procedures, and documentation for compliance and risk mitigation related to SOC3
- Skill Building: Learned Scala quickly on the job to match the primary language the Data Engineers use; learned and helped run a course with one of the Data Engineers to teach Airflow to coworkers

Charles Schwab (Apex Systems) Business Analyst

San Francisco, CA / Remote May 2020 - May 2021

- Front-End UI: Worked with developers test a new front-end UI to display trade orders for portfolio managers
- SQL/QA Validation: Queried databases using SQL to validate data while conducting UAT and QA testing and question/improve UI functionality and efficiency
- Testing: Gathered testing requirements for trade order processing flow so each flow variation could be tested thoroughly
- Agile/Scrum: Lead daily project scrum calls to ensure timely competition of user stories and appropriate allocation of resources
- **Flexibility:** Filled in gaps on teams and worked on various projects related to testing vendor account and trade management system and migrating ETF trade order processing file
- Documentation: Created production support documentation for import and export feeds for trading systems

JPMorgan Chase & Co. Business Data Analyst / Associate

New York, NY February 2016 - June 2019

- Analysis: Analyzed and managed primary and secondary sourced data for the US Funds Management Data Warehouse (FMDW), specifically minimizing data errors for the Finance Team for financial reporting purposes
- Source Data: Led and assisted with projects to maintain data feeds of sourced data for FMDW, and to streamline, automate and improve new downstream data feeds to other business units
- **Communication:** Communicated and coordinated with various lines of business, and served as a liaison between business and technology to help improve business processes and drive changes to the ETL
- Data Quality: Used SAP Business Objects to query data for analysis, reporting (daily, monthly, quarterly), UAT testing, and data quality purposes
- Infrastructure: Maintained SAP Business Objects infrastructure and data model/data mapping for FMDW
- **International:** Worked with international teams from Europe and Asia
- Training: Helped train new and junior team members

- Data Maintenance: Maintained and updated data on multiple systems including Perform, Charles River, SEI and SMART, containing thousands of accounts and tens of thousands of securities, for the Wealth Management Fixed Income trading desk
- Risk Mitigation: Managed and mitigated risk for Wealth Management Fixed Income trading desk by maintaining data and data flow for multiple systems through reconciliation reporting
- **SQL:** Updated, adjusted, and created new SQL queries to find specific data for ad hoc or future needs
- Vendor Relations: Worked directly with vendor on application updates and new features to meet end user needs

EverFi Inc. Services and Curriculum Intern

Newton, MA

June 2013 - May 2014

Tech Support: Performed Level-2 Technical Support and testing for technology-based education platforms

Education

University of California, Berkeley

Berkeley, CA

Certificate in Data Analytics and Visualization

January 2021

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in Excel, VBA, Python, R, JavaScript, SQL Databases, Tableau, Big Data, and Machine Learning

Suffolk University Sawyer Business School

Boston, MA

Bachelor of Science in Business Administration Management, Information Systems minor Awards: Magna Cum Laude | GPA: 3.77

May 2014